hi i'm tom nunn from manulife financial
i'm here today with moisture malevsky
maisha is a tenured professor at york
university executive director of the ifa
center and ceo of the cuima group he's
also recently released his eighth book
entitled pensionize your nest egg how to
use product allocation to create a
guaranteed income for life
marcia let's discuss some of the ideas
you introduce in your newest book
do you believe many canadians are
overestimating the type of pension they
have and if so what can they do about it
sure it's not so much a belief as much
as a fact actually when you talk to
people and ask them what type of pension
they have more often they're not they're
likely to underestimate the amount of
income that they're going to be able to
draw from their pension and even the
type of pension that they have and these
studies have been replicated in the u.s
as well basically a pension is a
guaranteed source of income for the rest
of their life as long as they live in
many cases it continues to the spouse
inflation protection longevity insurance
and very few canadians have it a lot of
people think that an rrsp is a pension
that's not true an rrsp is a tax
sheltered investment plan they think
that the group rrsp that they have at
work is a pension it isn't it's just an
investment plan a defined contribution
plan is not a pension a capital
accumulation plan is not a pension these
are all investment and savings plan a
pension has a number of unique
characteristics and unless you satisfy
those characteristics guarantees and
predictability and insurance and
protection you don't have a pension and
unfortunately many canadians in fact the
majority of canadians in the labor force
do not have a pension now do they still
need product allocation and
pensionization if they seem to have
enough money saved and set aside for the
retirement year that's a good question
tom in fact that gets to the heart of
the matter in the book pensionize your
nest egg when you have a substantial sum
of money in your rrsp that's all you
have and that is money and the point is
you have to turn that into income into
flow and as you get closer to retirement
you have to figure out how to do that
and that's where product allocation
comes into play we find that it's the
people that have very very large rrsps
that are most likely to need some sort
of product allocation if you have very
little money in your rrsp
chances are it's because you have a
great pension at work and you don't have
any room in your rrsps the people that
have the large rrsps are probably the
ones that will most benefit from
pensionization excellent moisture thanks
for your time today sure my pleasure